Guide to the Waltraude Woods, Senior Architect/Planner, Yale University, Records Documenting the History of Yale Buildings and Grounds
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Waltraude Woods, senior architect/planner, Yale University, records documenting the history of Yale buildings and grounds
1701-2004
RU 965
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
27
The records consist of maps, studies, news clippings, research notes, presentation panels, and assorted data compiled by Waltraude (Val) Woods, senior architect/planner at Yale Office of Facilities, documenting the history of campus planning and buildings and grounds at Yale University.
Yale University. Office of Facilities
Woods, Waltraude
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-A (YRG 46-A), Records and materials broadly documenting Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of Facilities, 2004-2006.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of maps, studies, news clippings, research notes, presentation panels, and assorted data compiled by Waltraude (Val) Woods, senior architect/planner at Yale Office of Facilities, documenting the history of campus planning and buildings and grounds at Yale University.
Campus planning; College buildings -- Design and construction; College buildings -- Maintenance and repair; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University. Office of Facilities
- Records documenting the history of buildings and grounds, circa 1701-2004; Inventory
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2039
  - Studies
    - 1942-1969 (Box 1)
    - 1986 (Box 2)
    - 1986-1989 (Box 3)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 4)
    - 1993-1995 (Box 5)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Data - Maps
    - 1700-1989 (Box 7)
    - 1990-2000 (Box 8)
    - 1900-1933 (Box 9)
    - 1934, 1967-1989 (Box 10)
    - 1990-1993 (Box 11)
    - 1994 (Box 12)
    - 1995-2000 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds of Yale University - update (BGYU)
    - Reference, 1919-1998 (Box 13a)
    - Summary, 1999 (Box 14)
    - Proposal (Box 15)
  - Clippings (Box 16)
  - Historic Resources Inventory, Connecticut Historical Commission (HIST INVENT 1980) (Box 17)
  - Reference Publications (REF PUB)
    - 1873-1976 (Box 18)
    - 1977-1989 (Box 19)
    - 1990-1997 (Box 20)
    - 1998-2000 (Box 21)
  - Reference - Residential (REF RES) (Box 22)
  - Research
    - Compiled, 1992-1997 (Box 23)
    - Manuscripts & Archives sources (Box 24)
    - Epochs of building and ground administration (Box 25)
    - Notes
      - 1923-1992 (Box 26)
      - 1993-1999 (Box 27)
      - 2000-2004 (Box 28)
- Presentation panels of buildings and grounds requiring maintenance, Undated; Accession 19ND-A-510
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025.
  - Twenty-one panels of photographs documenting details of buildings and grounds requiring repairs and maintenance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Miscellaneous files of Val Woods concerning the history of Yale University buildings and grounds, circa 1997- 2000; Accession 2006-A-227
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2035
  - Misc. files of Val Woods concerning the history of Yale University buildings and grounds, circa 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)